ket.org 2019-12-12

# KET Online Privacy Policy > KET

KET respects your privacy. We are committed to protecting the private information of visitors to our KET.org website and to any direct KET affiliate websites, such as ketfastforward.org (collectively, the “Site”). BY USING OR VISITING THE SITE OR ANY KET PRODUCT, SOFTWARE, DATA FEED, OR SERVICE PROVIDED TO YOU ON, FROM OR THROUGH THE SITE (COLLECTIVELY, THE “SERVICES”), YOU SPECIFICALLY AGREE TO ABIDE BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND [THE TERMS OF USE](http://portal-staging.ket.org/terms-of-use/) AND ANY MODIFICATIONS THERETO.

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR THE TERMS OF USE, PLEASE DO NOT USE THIS SITE OR THE SERVICES.

## **1\. Overview**

### **A. What the Policy Covers**

This Policy describes the types of information that we may collect or you may provide when you are on the Site. This Policy will also describe KET’s protocol for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information. This Policy applies only to information KET collects in connection with the Site.

### **B. What isn’t covered by the Policy**

Please note that the Site may contain links to sponsor organizations and affiliated entities. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of those websites. Other websites and third parties have their own privacy policies and we encourage you to read them if you have left the Site and have entered another website. This Policy also DOES NOT apply to information that KET collects from any other source or that you may provide to or is collected by any third party.

## **2\. Gathering and Use of Information**

### **A. Overview**

  1. _We do not collect any personally identifiable information from you other than what you supply voluntarily._
  2.  _Some site activities may require registration or ask you to submit some personally identifiable information, including but not limited to your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, payment information, last four digits of your social security number, or birthdate. In each case, we will ask ONLY for the necessary information. Examples of such activities include:_
    1.  _educational services, such as KET FastForward, Online Campus distance learning Programs, and Professional Development;_
    2.  _donating to KET;_
    3.  _commenting on videos, articles, or other content;_
    4.  _subscribing to e-mail newsletters or requesting program reminder e-mails._

### **B. No Sale or Trade of Information about Users or Donors**

WE NEVER SELL OR TRADE INFORMATION ABOUT OUR USERS OR DONORS. The only outside parties with whom your information is shared are those hired by or partnering with KET to complete a transaction in which you have chosen to participate, such as taking an educational course, making a donation, or requesting an email newsletter or reminder. These vendors are contractually obligated to keep your information completely confidential.

### **C. When Disclosure of Personal Information is Necessary or Appropriate**

KET, and third parties with whom we partner, may disclose information about you or your use of our Site when we deem it necessary or appropriate:

  1. _to comply with the law or a legal process, or when we have received a valid administrative request from a law enforcement agency, or in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings;_
  2.  _to respond to claims;_
  3.  _to ensure the integrity and operation of our business and systems;_
  4.  _to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk); or_
  5.  _to protect the rights, property, systems, or safety of KET or others._

Such disclosure may include personally identifiable information.

### **D. Third Party Service Providers**

In certain cases, we contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf. These service providers may maintain customer databases which may hold personally identifiable information, as described in paragraph 2.A.2 of this Policy, of such site users as:

  1. _Site visitors who have provided personally identifiable information to KET by registering at our Site or signing up for a newsletter or listserv;_
  2.  _audience members who e-mail questions about membership or programs;_
  3.  _donors who submit online contributions; or_
  4.  _online buyers who make a purchase._

We, or our service providers, will use this personally identifiable information to respond to the general purposes for which the information was collected, to provide services and to operate the Site, which might include responding to inquiries; processing credit card payments; managing billing, shipping, e-mail distribution, list processing and analysis, and promotions; sending information about KET programs, Site, services, membership; or corresponding about a purchase or product offer. For example, a third party fulfillment agent may be used to manage orders, credit card processing, order fulfillment and shipping, and related tasks.

Our service providers have access to your personally identifiable information as necessary to provide certain services on our behalf. They are required to maintain the privacy of all such information in their possession or control and can only use the information on our behalf for the purpose for which we have contracted with them, such as processing your order or sending you an e-mail. They are not authorized to use your information for any other purpose.

Similarly, personally identifiable information provided in connection with a donation intended for a program, series or KET, or for purposes of ordering products, subscriptions or other services offered by KET, will be shared by KET with third parties who perform services to process the donation or the applicable order. Also, upon receiving your donation or order, KET may share your personally identifiable information with a third party service provider for processing, as well as for market research and outreach purposes.

### **E. Information you disclose on the Site**

On certain pages, we offer visitors the opportunity to provide comments or other user-generated content. Any information that you disclose when posting a message to these areas, along with the screen name or ID used, becomes public. In addition, the information that you disclose in these areas may be used by us for promotional and marketing purposes. We are not responsible for any personally identifiable information that you choose to disclose in these public areas.

### **F. Using your personal data**

Personal data submitted on this Site will be used for the purposes specified in this Policy or in relevant parts of the Site. In addition to the uses identified elsewhere in this Policy, we may use your personal information to:

  1. _improve your browsing experience by personalizing the Site;_
  2.  _send you information (other than marketing communications) that we think may be of interest to you by regular mail or by e-mail or similar technology;_
  3.  _send you marketing communications relating to our business or the businesses of carefully-selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you by regular mail, e-mail or similar technology; and_
  4.  _provide other companies with statistical information about our users – but this information will not be used to identify any individual user._

## **3\. Your Privacy Rights**

_**Limited “Opt Out”**_. KET, and third parties with whom we partner, may occasionally use some personally identifiable information about you for our own internal promotion, marketing, and fund-raising purposes. You may, for instance, be invited to subscribe to a newsletter related to your already expressed interests or reminded that a contribution is due for renewal. We will typically explain the extent of use at the time you are asked to provide personal information. If you do not want this information to be collected or used by us for these purposes, you can simply “opt out.” Under certain circumstances, opting out may prevent your participation in activities for which personal information is needed, such as registering for contests or drawings.

**We offer several e-mail newsletters. If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, you may opt out by following the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter.**

**We reserve the right to send you e-mail relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of credit card problems, and other transactional e-mails and notifications about major changes to our Site. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive e-mail specific to your participation in those activities.**

_**“Opt In” for KET PASSPORT.**_ If you register for KET PASSPORT, a video on demand service, you will supply your name and e-mail address to KET and that information will be shared with our public broadcasting partner, PBS. PBS or a third party service provider may have access to your name, e-mail address, membership expiration date, member identification number, and membership start date. PBS or a third party service provider will generate information for KET including but not limited to what programs you are watching online, how frequently you watch and what device you are using. PBS and KET may use that data for targeted messaging, as well as other opportunities to improve your viewing experience. To register for KET PASSPORT you will be required to click “Continue” which will constitute your agreement to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use. You may withdraw from KET PASSPORT by sending an e-mail to membership@KET.org or calling 1-800-866-0366. **If you do not want KET or a third party service provider to have access to, use or share the types of data described in this paragraph, do not register for KET PASSPORT.**

## **4\. Tracking and Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies**

Like most websites, our Site and Services may incorporate technology such as “cookies,” “pixel tags,” and “Web beacons” that allow us to track the actions of users of our Services. Cookies, pixel tags, and Web beacons collect non-personal data.

**_Cookies_.** A cookie is a small text file sent by a Web server to a Web browser, and stored by the browser. The text file is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the Web server to identify and track the Web browser. A cookie may be stored on your computer’s hard drive. You may be able to set your Web browser to reject cookies entirely or require that it request permission from you before accepting each new cookie. You can also delete cookies from your hard drive once you leave a website.  
We, and third party service providers, use anonymous cookies to record non-personal data such as Site and Service activity, date and time of visit, domain type, IP address and demographic information (zip codes for example). All data is anonymous and cannot be used to identify the visitor. The information obtained from the cookie may be used in the administration of the Site, tailoring the Site to the interests and locations of the users, measuring traffic within the Site, improving the Site’s usability and for marketing purposes. We may also use that information to recognize your computer when you visit our Site, and to personalize our Site for you. KET may also use the content from cookies to deliver relevant local resources, remember browser preferences, and improve our visitors’ experiences on the Site. KET does not sell information collected by cookies.

We work with advertising partners relating to advertisements on the Services. One of the services we use to track activity related to the Services, e.g., by placing cookies, is Google Analytics by Google (Google, Inc. a company headquartered at 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). We may use vendors, including Google, who use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on your past visits to our websites, including Google Analytics for Display Advertising. Google provides tools to manage the collection and use of certain information by Google Analytics at [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and by Google Analytics for Display Advertising or the Google Display Network by using Google’s Ads Settings at <http://www.google.com/settings/ads> .

_**Similar Technologies**_. We, and third party service providers, also use pixel tags and web beacons which are tracking devices on websites or in e-mails that can monitor the behavior of the user visiting the website or receiving the e-mail. There is no accepted standard on how to respond to Do Not Track signals, and we do not respond to such signals.

KET may utilize user-behavior information and other non-personally identifiable information, such as IP addresses or demographics like zip codes, to tailor our Site to the interests/locations of our users and to measure traffic within the Site. Non-personal data will also be collected, and shared with third party service providers to provide relevant advertisements through retargeting. Retargeting recognizes that the internet browser has visited the website. All data is anonymous and cannot be used to identify the visitor.

**There is no ability to “opt out” from retargeting or being tracked on this Site. If you do not want this type of data to be collected on you, do not use the Site or the Services.**

## **5\. Security of Your Personal Data**

We will take reasonable precautions to prevent the unauthorized access or disclosure of your personal information. No security or encryption method can be guaranteed to protect information from a hacker or from human error.

We will store all of the personal information you provide on our secure servers. Third party service providers may also store your login or password for any third party applications. You are responsible for keeping your passwords confidential. We will not ask you for your passwords.

## **6\. Our Policy regarding Children**

The Site is a general audience Site and does not knowingly collect or solicit personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register on the Site. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register or send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address. No one under the age of 13 may provide any personal information to us. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information without parental consent, please contact [feedback@ket.org](mailto:feedback@ket.org) . If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information without parental consent, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child’s account.

We endeavor to obtain a parent or legal guardian’s consent before collecting, using, or disclosing personal information from children. Parents or legal guardians may contact us to ask if we have collected their child’s personal account information, to review that information, if any, to request that KET stop collecting this information and/or to have the information deleted. Such requests are subject to KET verifying to our satisfaction that the requester is in fact the child’s parent or legal guardian.

## **7\. Accessing or Correcting your Personal Information**

You can always correct or update your personally identifiable information. You can review and change your name, e-mail address, and communication preferences by clicking on “MANAGE MY COMMUNICATIONS” near the bottom of each newsletter. To change other data, please contact [feedback@ket.org](mailto:feedback@ket.org).

KET may be required to maintain certain records and may be prohibited from expunging certain data from its system .

## **8\. Acceptance of KET’s Privacy Policy and Terms of Use; Changes to KET Privacy Policy and Terms of Use**

By using this Site, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this KET Privacy Policy and [the Terms of Use. ](http://portal-staging.ket.org/terms-of-use/)

**IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS, PLEASE DO NOT USE THE SITE.**

We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add to, or remove portions of this Policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for any changes. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of any changes to these terms shall mean that you have accepted those changes. If you have any questions or concerns, please e-mail us at [feedback@ket.org](mailto:feedback@ket.org).

## **9\. Notice to California Residents**

California Business & Professions Code Section 22575 (b) provides that California residents are entitled to know how KET responds to “Do Not Track” browser settings. KET does not currently take action to respond to Do Not Track signals because a uniform technological standard has not been created. KET continues to monitor technological standards.

If you are a California resident you are entitled to receive, once a year, information identifying the categories of Personal Information we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes and the contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties (under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84). If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this information, please submit a written request to [feedback@ket.org](mailto:feedback@ket.org). Please include your name and email address in your request.

Revised July 27, 2017
